Guide to the Papers of Abby Weed Grey 1922-1978 MC 151
New York University Archives
Abby Weed Grey Papers
1922-1978
MC 151
New York University Archives
16.0 linear feet
The Abby Weed Grey Papers span the years 1922-1978, with the bulk of the material covering the period 1960-1974. The papers document Mrs. Grey's world travels, published and unpublished works, and her collection and curation of art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in series determined before the collection arrived at the University Archives.
Book Copy
Unpublished Works
AWG Notebooks, 1945-1978
Travel Diaries, 1960-1973
Artist Files
Index Cards, 1947-1978
Misc. Activities and Memorabilia, 1959-1975
Correspondence
Tanavoli, Parviz
Grey Gallery and Study Center NYU
The University of Minnesota
The Grey Foundation
Scrapbooks
The Grey Foundation Exhibitions 1961-1972
Oversized materials
Multimedia
Abby Weed Grey Photographs
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Portrait and Biographical Files in the New York University Archives
New York University Photograph Collection, NYU Buildings, Grey Gallery and Study Center
"Abby Weed Grey," page from the Grey Art Gallery web site: http://www.nyu.edu/greyart/information/Abby_Weed_Grey/body_abby_weed_grey.html
The following reference materials:
Grey, Abby Weed. The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture: An Autobiographical Journey. New York: New York University Press, 1983.
One World Through Art: A Selection of 1001 Works of Art from the Ben and Abby Grey Foundation. St. Paul, Minn.: Ben and Abby Grey Foundation, 1972.
Scope and Contents
The Abby Weed Grey Papers span the years 1922-1978, with the bulk of the material covering the period 1960-1974. These papers illustrate Mrs. Grey's world travels and her interest in art. Documentation is most extensive pertaining to the writing of her autobiography entitled The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture: An Autobiographical Journey. They also provide information on the Iranian artist-sculptor Parviz Tanavoli and Mrs. Grey's gift to New York University to fund the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center. The collection also contains some material related to her earlier life.
Materials in Series I - XV include published and unpublished materials of Abby Weed Grey's writing; information on international artists; correspondence between Grey and artists, in particular Parviz Tanavoli; catalogs, publicity and clippings pertaining to exhibitions; and scrapbooks and oversized materials. Materials in Series XVI include magnetic tapes and reel to reels of varying sizes. Materials in Series XVII include photos of works of art in her collection and exhibitions, personal photos, and snapshots taken traveling abroad.
Biography of Abby Weed Grey
Abby Weed Grey, the oldest of four children, was born on October 23, 1902, to Henry and Emily Weed in St. Paul, Minnesota. She grew up in St. Paul, attending both elementary and high school there. In 1920, Abby headed off east where she attended Vassar College, a private all women's college in Poughkeepsie, New York. After graduating in 1924, Abby spent the next few years (what she considered her "wander years") traveling abroad with a college roommate to Riga, Latvia, and Paris, France. Following her return from Paris in 1926, Abby started teaching fifth grade in a private school for girls in Kansas City. It was at this time that she met Lieutenant Colonel Benjamin Edwards Grey. In 1928 she became engaged and a year later married Benjamin Grey, 20 years her senior. For the next 27 years she lived as an Army wife, traveling on cross-country trips and entertaining. During that time, her husband invested in Western railroad stocks and bonds. In 1947 they purchased their first home, the family cabin in Deer Lake, Minnesota. They moved between Minnesota and Salt Lake City, Utah. In 1956 Ben died of cancer in St. Paul, Minnesota.
After Ben's death, Abby moved back to St. Paul, Minnesota. Before leaving she established the annual Benjamin Edwards Grey Memorial Lecture in poetry as part of the Summer Writers' Conference at the University of Utah.
In 1960, after being widowed for four years, Abby Grey took her first trip around the world with a group of thirteen women to Japan, Hong Kong, Thailand, Cambodia, India, Kashmir, Nepal, Pakistan, Iran, and Israel. In these foreign countries, some nearly totally unaware of Western influence, Mrs. Grey began her search for an innovative artist by meeting with working with local artists and collecting contemporary art to be shown in America.
One year later Mrs. Grey established The Ben & Abby Grey Foundation, Inc., founded for the encouragement of art through the assembling of international collections of art for cultural exchange programs. Also in 1961 she founded the "Minnesota Art Portfolio" exhibit (MAP) as an opportunity for artists to see original works by their Western counterparts. She met with Malcolm Lein, the director of the St. Paul Art Center, and selected Minnesota artists' works to bring on a trip to Spain, Greece, Italy, Turkey, and Iran. Through the United States Information Service (USIS) and the People-to-People Program, the exhibit traveled throughout the Middle East and the Mediterranean for two years. During her trip to Iran with MAP, Abby met Bishop Hassan Dehqani-Tafti of St. Luke's Church while attending Anglican services.
One artist in whom Mrs. Grey took particular interest was Iranian artist-sculptor Parviz Tanavoli, whom she met in 1961. The following year the Grey Foundation provided him a grant for six months as a visiting artist at the Minneapolis School of Art. He remained as a sculptor/instructor on staff for the following two years. In June 1964 Tanavoli returned to Iran with the gift of a bronze foundry for the University of Tehran given by the Grey Foundation.
Throughout the rest of the 1960s and early 1970s Mrs. Grey initiated many projects. These included "Fourteen Contemporary Iranians" (1962-65), which toured American cities, as did "Turkish Art Today" (1966-70), which also traveled to Tehran, Iran. Communication through Art, comprised of three exhibitions of American work, opened simultaneously in 1964 in Istanbul, Tehran, and Lahore and traveled for five years in the eastern Mediterranean, Asia, and eastern Africa. This program, which complemented the goals of USIS, was accompanied by books and catalogues representing the American art scene. Mrs. Grey also sponsored the American section of the India Triennial of Contemporary World Art in 1968. Two years later she co-sponsored it with New York's Museum of Modern Art. In 1972, "One World Through Art," an exhibition of 1,001 works from Mrs. Grey's collection, was shown at the Minnesota State Fair Grounds.
As Mrs. Grey's collection grew, she sought a place to exhibit her collection and share it with other people. At first, Mrs. Grey looked for a home for her art in her own locality. The University of Minnesota was ruled out because the gallery space available was inconvenient and the school administrators would have run the gallery. Mrs. Grey also looked at her alma mater, Vassar College, but finally chose New York University, because it gave her the flexibility that she wanted. Also, since her collection was a unique, New York City seemed the ideal place to house it. The Ben and Abby Grey Foundation, founded for the encouragement of art, donated one million dollars to NYU and in the spring of 1975, the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center was completed.
Four years later, Mrs. Grey again donated money to NYU for an art history study center that was built on the third floor of main building. In addition to the Gallery and Study Center, Mrs. Grey provided the funds to renovate the NYU undergraduate art history classrooms, auditorium and faculty offices.
By 1979, Abby Grey had become one of the foremost collectors of Asian and Middle Eastern art. She had made nine trips to Asia and had collected over 600 artworks from native artists in Egypt, Greece, Iran, India, Japan, Turkey, Pakistan, and her hometown of St. Paul, Minnesota.
On June 2, 1983, Abby Weed Grey died of cancer in St. Paul at the age of 80 years.
Throughout her life, as a patron to the arts, Mrs. Grey served on The Minnesota Society of Fine Arts (the governing body of the Minnesota Institute of Arts) Board of Trustees from 1967-73 and on the Minneapolis College of Art and Design's Board of Overseers from 1964 until her death. She established Abby Weed Grey scholarships at the College as well. At the Walker Art Center she endowed the Grey Fellowship in Museum Studies. At Hamline University she helped sponsor symposia in Near Eastern Studies and has been a benefactor to St. Catherine's College and the St. Paul Academy-Summit School. She was a member of The Women's Club of Minneapolis and The Cosmopolitan Club of New York.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. This collection is stored onsite.
Provenance
The papers of Abby Weed Grey were transferred from the Grey Study Center Library of New York University to the University Archives in the Spring of 1998.
Ben and Abby Grey Foundation.; Grey Art Gallery & Study Center.; Grey, Abby Weed, 1902-1983; Minneapolis Institute of Arts.; Minneapolis Society of Fine Arts.; Tanavoli, Parviz; University of Minnesota.; Army spouses.; Art museums |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art objects |x Collectors and collecting.; Art patrons.; Art |x Collectors and collecting.; Art, Iranian.; Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Exhibitions.; Art, Turkish.; Artists and patrons.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Exhibition catalogs.; Grey Art Gallery & Study Center.; Islamic art |z Middle East.; Manuscripts (document genre).; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; University of Minnesota.
- Series I: Book Copy
  - Subseries A: Edited, 1960-1979
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains edited drafts of Abby Weed Grey's book, published in 1983, The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture. They are arranged in page order and chronological order beginning with her "early years" pages 1-39. The dates included in the manuscript begin in 1902 (her birth) with earlier dates for family history. Last date on copy is 1979. Also included are notes on the organization of the book and notes on writing a book.
    - Early Years pp.1-39, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      3 1142 04225385 9
    - 1st Trip Around the World, pp.40-67, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2nd Trip, Em & Hilly, pp. 68-90, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 3rd Trip "Art Form of the Ancient World", pp.91-96 & 4th Trip "Communication Through Art", pp.96-122, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 5th Trip Jane Gregory, pp.124-165, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 6th Trip with Ted, pp.166-203, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 7th Trip Ellen Johnson Triennale, pp.204-230, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 8th Trip Mike, Ruth, Bettina, Turkey, pp.232-266, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - pp.267-280, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Last Trip, 9th, pp.281-295, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interim Sections, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Final Chapter: The Gift, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Organization of Book, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Communication Through Art", MSS Draft, pp.1-88, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Association & Correspondence, 1975-1981
    Contains correspondence about the draft of her book. These letters include notes for the book, the outline and structure of the book, and edited pages of book.
    - "1960,61,62 Notes (in 54 sets) About Writing a Book trans., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Jeff Bedou interview with Abby Weed Grey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Notes on Book from Sylvia Rosen, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Letty Grierson, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with Nancy Ann James, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Book Outline from History Ink, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence Re: Book Publication, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous MS Pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series II: Unpublished Works, 1941-1975
  Contains 7 poetry notebooks, 2 poetry small binders, 1 black binder with notes, pictures, short stories, and articles. One black binder, a scrapbook, has been separated and moved to Box 8. These notebooks and binders consist of writings about her life.
  - Early Poems (Mystical and Lyrical), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1941 Outline of John Dewey; Short Stories; St. Mark's Church Work, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notes on St. Mark's Cathedral Church, John Dewey *See Box 8, Fldr 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Binder of Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Binder of Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Poetry: Exercises and Rewrites, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Eye to the Sooty Crack by Abby Weed Grey, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Poetry in Precise Language", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "An Eagle Came Over", 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Poetry is Change", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225386 7
  - Corrected Notes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Search for Other-Then-I", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Excerpts from notebooks, writings, etc., 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Pure Eye," "Who Am I," "The Electric Welcome," "Sand Paintings," What Do I Attend," "Prelude to Reality", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Need for a Feeling of Spontaneity", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Poems, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "About Time and Space", 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Deer Down from the Mountains", 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Thoughts on Power", 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Ben's Last Time at Deer Lake", 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Captiva", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Ben's Last Weeks on Captiva", 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Seven Last Words of my Mother", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Early Education; Years at Vassar College", undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Houses I Have Lived In", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Memos from my letters from Vassar (1920), undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Resumes of letters to family from "Wander Year", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Poetry-generated by "Tour of Ancient World", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "The Minnesota State Fair", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "My Wander Year (1925-26)", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "First Art Purchases", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (incorporated in other works), undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series III: AWG Notebooks 1945-1978
  Contain spiral and unbound notebooks and copies of notebooks arranged chronologically by date. These consist of notes, poetry, journal entries, essays, descriptions of travel, and information regarding artists, MAP, USIA, and Parviz Tanavoli (see biographical description).
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1956-1956 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Copies of Notebooks (edited), 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook (partially edited), 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook (USIA, MAP, Parviz), 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, Jun 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225387 5
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, Aug 1967-Dec 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, Dec 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, Jul 1973, 1974 May (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, Apr 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Travel Diaries 1960-1973
  Contains diaries of travels (originals, edited, and copies), poems, and a photo essay/diary which has been separated and removed to Box 8.
  - Abby Weed Grey: Summaries of Nine Diaries, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Travel Diary (1st) * See Separation Box, Fldr. 1, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Travel Diary (incomplete transcripts), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited) *See Separation Box, Fldr. 2, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Travel Diary (and Poems), Mar 1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Diary (rewritten in Abby's hand), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Travel Diary (mss & edited copy), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Travel Diary (original, copy & edited)* See Separation Box, Fldr. 3, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Travel Diary (taped transc. & edited), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Photo Essay/Diary *See Photo Collection, Box 5, Fldr. 3, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Series V: Artist Files
  Contains information regarding international artists, including correspondence, published materials regarding their work, clippings, artist profiles, pamphlets. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject/country, with most in English, although some in other languages including French and languages of the country represented. It is divided into six subseries.
  - Subseries A: General Information
    Contains general information on artists AWG associated with including a catalog, correspondence and index cards with information on specific artists mentioned in her diaries.
    - Cultural Profiles, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Grey Collection Catalogues (with additions), 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Artists Bios, "Deep Roots", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Artists Mentioned in Diaries (Date and Place), undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Artist Letter, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Subseries B: Greece
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence, and biographical information on specific Greek artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Guinis, Alkis *See Photo Collection, Box 4, Fldr 14, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Houtopoulou-Contaratou, Sosso, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Kimball, Yeffe (USA Native Amer.), undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Klonaris, Marilena, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Vakalo, G., undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Spyropoulos, Jannis *See Separation Box, Fldr. 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Subseries C: India
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence and biographical information on specific Indian artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Ambadas, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225388 3
    - Appasamy, Jaya, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ali, J. Sultan, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bagat, Dhan Raj, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Bakre, Sadanand K., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Barwe, Prabha Kar, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bhatt, Jyoti, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Bhavsar, Natvar, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Bhusan, Sudhiranjan, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Bisht, Ramesh, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Ghandra, Avinash, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bisht, Ranvir S., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Dasgupta, Bimal, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dave, Shanti, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Gaitonde, V. S., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Hore, Somnath, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Gujral, Satish, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Gupta, Ram, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Husain, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Jatindas, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Kar, Sanat, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Khakkar, Bhupen, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Khanna, Krishen, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Khanna, Krisha, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Krishna, Devayani, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Krishna, Kanwal, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lewis, Peter, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Mehta, Tyeb, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Mitra, Gopal, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Pai, Laxman, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Padamsee, Akbar *See Photo Collection, Box 4, Fldr.15, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Palsikar, S.B., undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Panchal, Naren, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Panchal, Satish, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Parikh, Jayant, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Patel, Homi, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Patel, Thakor, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Prakash, Om, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Rama Rao, S.U., undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Reddy, Krishna, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Sabavala, Jehangir, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Sagara, Piraji, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Samant, Mohan, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Santosh, Gumal Rasool, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Shah, Haku, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Sihare, Laxmi Pradas, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Souza, F.N., undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Swaminathan, J., undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Vivasvan, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Vazifdar, J.P., undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Subseries D: Iran
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence, and biographical information on specific Iranian artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Armanjani, Siah, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Diba, Kamram, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Fizian, Aziz, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Ghandriz, Mansour, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Grigorian, Marco, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Khamenei, Hossein Musavi, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Nami, Ghoiamhose In, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Ovissi, Nasser, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Pilaram, Faramarz, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Sakarians, Sarkis, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Sassoon, Sirous, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Sepehri, Sohrab, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Shabazi, Shahrokh *See Box 8, Fldr 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Spooner, Senobar, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Tabatabai, Jazeh, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Vartanian, Hacob, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Zarrine, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Zenderoudi, Hossin, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Subseries E: Tunis
    Contains a general pamphlet on Tunisian artists.
    - General Pamphlet on Artists, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Subseries F: Turkey
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence and biographical information on specific Turkish artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Basaran, Filiz, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Boronai, Aliye Berger, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Ã?etinkaya, Orhan, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Eyüboglu, Bedri Rahmi, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Gursoy, Ahmet, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Kilic, Asuman, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Marini, Aida, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)